TRIPTI WANI

Web Developer

Telephone +61 481 254 765 Email tripti.895@gmail.com Sydney, Australia Address Website triptiwani.github.io

PROFILE

I am a web developer with a strong interest in projects that require both conceptual and analytical thinking. I love to solve problems with code while applying industry best practices in a collaborative environment. Fully- committed to designing and developing innovative web-based materials that users will love. Focused and self-motivated professional, with 7 years experience in Information Technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTMI CSS

lavascript Ajax

jQuery Backbone.js

Ruby Three.is

Ruby on Rails Underscore.js

Bootstrap SQL/Postgres

Git/Heroku TDD - Rspec,

UNIX Scripting Cucumber

Stencyl RESTful APIS

EDUCATION

2016 - 2016

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, Sydney

2004 - 2008

M.Sc. (Hons.) - Integrated Course BITS Pilani, India

REFERENCES

Joel Turnbull, Instructor, GA Bala R., RXP Services Limited

HIGHLIGHT

SIGNMEUP - SheHacks2016 organised by GirlGeekSydney

All Women Hackathon- SheHacks - brought together 50 developers, designers, UX and producers working in small groups to come up with digital ideas and prototypes. Built a sign language translator app for people with hearing loss and received Third place.

Tech Stack Web Speech API, Natural Language Processing **Link** http://site-55311-9163-8820.strikingly.com

EXPERIENCE

CODE CAMP

Spring Holidays 2016

Teaching Assistant

Assisted the Head Teacher, troubleshooted the issues faced by kids. Helped kids develop logic, computational thinking, user experience, creativity by problem solving while building apps and games.

Tech Stack Stencyl

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

June 2016 - Sep 2016

General Assembly is a pioneer in education and career transformation, specialising in today's most in-demand skills.

TALK2ME

User friendly web-based chat application covering photos, gifs and location with a Mobile-first approach.

Tech Stack HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,Ruby,Rails 5, Puma/ Redis, Cloudinary/Bootstrap, Gifshot.js, Google Maps.js

Link https://talk2meapp.herokuapp.com

PALATE

A mobile-first app for creating, bookmarking and sharing recipes from any existing recipe websites via chrome extension.

Tech Stack HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,Ruby/Rails 4.2.6,Nokogiri, Cloudinary/ Bootstrap, bcrypt, httparty, ratyrate, Chrome Dev tool, Padilicious. js

Link https://wdi15project2.herokuapp.com

INVENTORY MANAGEMENT

This is an e-commerce website to procure, track and deal in Mobile handsets and accessories for wholesalers and retailers across multiple locations with the built-in payment feature.

Tech Stack HTML/CSS/Javascript/jQuery,Ruby /Rails 4.2.6, Cloudinary/ Sendgrid, Stripe.js, Money-rails, Twitter/Facebook/bcrypt **Link** https://store-inventory-management.herokuapp.com

INFOSYS LIMITED

July 2008 - Sep 2015

Infosys Limited is an Indian multinational corporation that provides business consulting, information technology and outsourcing services.

Software Engineer

Worked on multiple projects across domains and technologies. My commitment and dedication helped me move to a Lead position really guickly.

- Worked on the ETL Framework migration for a prestigious AUS Bank
- Interactions with the Business to analyse, design and understand the technical requirements applicable during SDLC
- Provide technical mentoring, perform reviews and contribute to functional and technical documents
- Planning/Tracking 24*7 production support cycle, analyse, suggest/implement work-around and perform Root Cause Analysis to avoid re-occurence of the issue.

Tech Stack Perl, Shell, Unix, Linux, Informatica, ETL